{
    "id": "8a59f7311891499e9a97104d1baa4266",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I always ................................... my grandmother on the weekends.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about habits, routines etc.",
            "answers": [
                "visit",
                "am visiting",
                "will visit"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The President ............................... the nation at 8 pm.",
            "description": "The present continuous is considered more appropriate here because the plan already exists. ",
            "answers": [
                "addresses",
                "is addressing",
                "will address"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The summer term ............................... in July.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about future events that are part of a time table. ",
            "answers": [
                "starts",
                "is starting",
                "will start"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He never .............................. his front door open.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habits, routines etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "is leaving",
                "leave",
                "leaves"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She ................................. immense joy from feeding stray animals.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk bout facts, likes, dislikes, habits, routines etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "gets",
                "is getting",
                "get"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He .................................. at gun point.",
            "description": "The passive verb is required here because the subject is not the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "robbed",
                "was robbed",
                "was robbing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "During the holidays, I ……………………. a lot of sleeping and eating.",
            "description": "Use the simple past to talk about a finished action or situation. ",
            "answers": [
                "was doing",
                "did",
                "have done"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I .................................... Janet in the afternoon.",
            "description": "Use the present continuous to talk about a future event when the plan already exists. ",
            "answers": [
                "meet",
                "am meeting",
                "have met"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Dad cooked dinner while Mom ................................. TV.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "is watching",
                "have watched"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You never let me .................................... a sentence.",
            "description": "Let is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "finish",
                "to finish",
                "finishing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................................ by UFOs.",
            "description": "A passive verb is required here.",
            "answers": [
                "always fascinated",
                "have always fascinated",
                "have always been fascinated"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Somebody ................................. at the gate.",
            "description": "Use the present continuous to talk about an ongoing action or situation. ",
            "answers": [
                "stands",
                "is standing",
                "has stood"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}